marinetraffic.com 2016-12-29

# Privacy Policy - AIS Data Services | AIS Marine Traffic

## Information Collection

The mission of MarineTraffic is to provide highly targeted Services to the world's maritime professionals and marine enthusiasts. To achieve this mission MarineTraffic makes features and functionality available through our website, including our mobile and other applications, API, premium services, and other information provided as part of the MarineTraffic services ("Services") to enable personalised access to our Data and networking features. Registering an account with MarineTraffic is optional. By registering with MarineTraffic, you voluntarily and willingly provide MarineTraffic certain information, including personally identifiable information, which we collect in order to provide the Services. If you have any hesitation about providing information to us and/or having your information displayed on the MarineTraffic website or otherwise used in any manner permitted in this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, you should not become a member of the MarineTraffic Services; and, if you are already a member, you should close your account.

A list of the Personal Information MarineTraffic may collect, and why we collect it, follows.

## Login information

In order to become a Member, you must provide us the following information to create an account:

Without this minimal amount of information, you cannot create a MarineTraffic account. Like other passwords, you should choose one that is known only by you.

## Profile information

During the Registration process you may provide additional information to your MarineTraffic profile describing your Personal and Professional status in respect to the maritime industry. Providing additional information about yourself beyond what is minimally required at Registration is optional, but providing additional information enables you to benefit more from MarineTraffic. Any information you provide at registration or in the Personal and Professional information sections may be used by MarineTraffic as described in the User Agreement and this Privacy Policy, including for the purpose of connecting you to other maritime professionals, or for serving more relevant advertisements on MarineTraffic. Certain Personal information such as your mobile number will be needed should you decide to use MarineTraffic's SMS alert services.

## Customer service and Sales

We collect information when you interact with MarineTraffic's Customer Service and Sales teams in order to accurately categorise and respond to your requests.

## Use of the Services

We receive information when you interact with and use the MarineTraffic website, MarineTraffic mobile applications and API. For example, we may log activity, e.g. when you rate photos, click on ads, install a MarineTraffic mobile application etc. If you have given permission to the MarineTraffic mobile application to use your device's location, we might also use this information for statistical purposes and to check you in a vessel or improve MarineTraffic tracking coverage.

## Cookies

Like most websites, we use cookies and web log files to track site usage and trends, to improve the quality of our service, to customize your experience on MarineTraffic, as well as to deliver MarineTraffic and third-party advertising to Users.

Cookies are small data files that a web site you visit may save on your hard drive. They usually include an anonymous unique identifier. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive or pass on computer viruses.

You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser, but in some cases doing so may prevent MarineTraffic from fully functioning. One type of cookie, known as a "persistent" cookie, is set once you've logged in to your MarineTraffic account. The next time you visit the MarineTraffic website, the persistent cookie will allow us to recognize you as an existing Member so you will not need to log in before using the Services, to display the Live Map as you last configured it etc.

We also use Google Analytics to help us understand how users use our web site and our mobile applications. Google Analytics cookies do not provide MarineTraffic with any personally identifiable information. They can tell us things like how you arrived at the MarineTraffic site, if you have visited the site before, how long you stay on the site, and which pages on the site you visited. They can also provide us with general information about where in the world a user may be located. This information helps us understand how people use our site and our products, and it gives us information about the kind of experience people have on our site and with our products, all of which helps us learn how to make the MarineTraffic experience even better.

Click [here](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html) to learn more about Google Analytics and your privacy. To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics when using our web-based products, click [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

We also use Google Analytics to help us understand how users use our web site and our mobile applications. Google Analytics cookies do not provide MarineTraffic with any personally identifiable information. They can tell us things like how you arrived at the MarineTraffic site, if you have visited the site before, how long you stay on the site, and which pages on the site you visited. They can also provide us with general information about where in the world a user may be located. This information helps us understand how people use our site and our products, and it gives us information about the kind of experience people have on our site and with our products, all of which helps us learn how to make the MarineTraffic experience even better.

## Local Storage

In addition to cookies, we are utilizing browser local storage technology to store your preferences and make your user experience more consistent. Local storage is a persistent type of storage, that provides similar functionality to cookies, but its contents are not transmitted across the Internet, like cookies are.

Like cookies, you can control how local storage works on your browser settings on a global or website specific manner. Disabling the local storage functionality on your browser will result in loss of functionality of the map and other features of the website.

## Social Media Features

Our website uses social media features ("Social Features") provided by companies and services such as Facebook, Twitter and Google+ to enable you to share information via these channels. The Social Features are identified on our website by these companies' respective logos. These cookies are owned and controlled by third parties, and therefore the third parties - and not MarineTraffic - are responsible for their use. As such, we can't guarantee that we have listed every cookie you might get from a third party since a third party could change these cookies at any time as their needs change.

When you visit a page on the MarineTraffic website that contains Social Features, your browser establishes a direct connection to the applicable social network's servers. The Social Features provide the social networks with the information that you have accessed on the MarineTraffic website, and, if you are logged into the social network, your visit may be logged to your account on that service. For example, if you click the Facebook "Like" button, that information is transmitted from your browser directly to Facebook and stored by it. Even if you are not logged into the social network, or click on a Social Feature on the MarineTraffic site, there is still a possibility that a Social Feature can transmit your IP address to the social network.

For information on the purpose and scope of data processing by the social network, as well as your options for protecting your privacy, please visit the appropriate social network web site's privacy policy:

## Email communication

From time to time, we may want to contact you with information about product announcements, software updates and special offers. We also may want to contact you with information about products and services from our business partners. You may opt out of such communications at any time by clicking the "unsubscribe" link found within MarineTraffic email updates.

Your e-mail address will not be used to send unsolicited commercial messages. Newsletters or other informative mail may be sent from MarineTraffic unless you explicitly oppose to this by submitting a request [here](http://help.marinetraffic.com/hc/en-us/requests/new).

## Third parties

MarineTraffic takes the privacy of our Users very seriously, and we do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties, except as described in this policy. We will also not share other personal information not published to your profile or generated through engagement with other MarineTraffic services without your explicit consent or to carry out your instructions (for example, to process payment information) unless, disclosure is reasonably necessary in our opinion to: (1) comply with legal process, including, but not limited to, civil and criminal subpoenas, court orders or other compulsory disclosures; (2) enforce this Agreement; (3) respond to claims of a violation of the rights of third parties, whether or not the third party is a User, individual, or government agency; (4) respond to customer service or sales inquiries; or (5) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of MarineTraffic, our Users or the public.

We may provide aggregated anonymous data about the usage of the Services to third parties for purposes that we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate, including to prospective advertisers on MarineTraffic.

## Member account

Upon finishing the registration process you will receive a confirmation e-mail with your chosen data at the e-mail address you provided.

Each user is personally and solely responsible for all actions and transactions made through his account. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and you should ensure that you exit properly from your account at the end of each session.

In case you notice any unauthorised use of your account or any other (real or potential) breach of security, you have to immediately notify the Website's administrators. MarineTraffic is under no circumstances liable for any loss or damages arising from your failure to comply with this term. MarineTraffic maintains the right to delete an account, if violation of any of these Terms is proved.

If you wish to deactivate your account please submit a request [here](http://help.marinetraffic.com/hc/en-us/requests/new).

## Data Storage and Security

MarineTraffic is committed to protecting the security of your information and takes reasonable precautions to protect it. However, Internet data transmissions, whether wired or wireless, cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and as a result, we cannot ensure the security of information you transmit to us; accordingly, you acknowledge that you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your data transmission, we make all commercially reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our systems:

Your MarineTraffic password is protected by encryption so that only you have access to it.

Your personal information and data stored in our systems is protected by various physical, electronic and procedural safeguards. It is housed in a secure facility, and MarineTraffic and our hosting partners restrict physical and network access to this facility to select trained staff. We regularly evaluate our technologies, facilities, procedures and potential risks to maintain the security and privacy of our users' data.

Certain MarineTraffic Services support the use of standard SSL encryption to protect data transmissions. However, this is not a guarantee that such data transmissions cannot be accessed, altered or deleted due to firewall or other security software failures.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

As MarineTraffic evolves, we may need to update this Policy to keep pace with changes in the Service and laws applicable to us and you; we will, however, always maintain our commitment to respect your privacy.

We will post any revisions to this Policy, so we recommend that you periodically check back here to stay informed of any changes. We will ask for your consent to such changes if required by applicable law; in other cases, please note that your continuation of your MarineTraffic Service account after any change means that you agree with, and consent to be bound by, the new Privacy Policy. If you disagree with any changes in this Policy and do not wish your information to be subject to the revised Policy, you will need to close your account before the new Policy becomes effective.

## How to contact us

MarineTraffic welcomes your feedback regarding this Privacy Policy. If you have questions, comments or concerns about this Policy, please contact us by submitting a request [here](http://help.marinetraffic.com/hc/en-us/requests/new) or postal mail at: _Exmile Solutions Limited, 1 Kings Avenue, London N21 3NA_.

You have the right to delete, reform, modify and update your Data. You can at any time deactivate your account by submitting a request [here](http://help.marinetraffic.com/hc/en-us/requests/new). You may contact us at the above address for any other information or objection you may have on data processing.
